

AARON DAY

SOFTWARE ENGINEER



(971) 706-7846 | aaron.day@mail.com | aaronday.info | linkedin.com/in/day-aaron

EXECUTIVE SUMMARY

3+ years' experience coding/programming and debugging in C, C++ and C# as well as JavaScript and Python scripting. Ability to learn quickly and work as part of a team. Former military professional with a strong work ethic, high attention to detail and a great desire to learn new skills, solve problems and think critically. Recently graduated with high honors from Oregon Institute of Technology with a Bachelor of Science in Software Engineering Technology.

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Programming: C/C++/C#, ASP.NET/.NET Core MVC, Razor/HTML 5, CSS 3, JavaScript/ECMAScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, LINQ/Microsoft SQL Server, Python, MatLab, MIPS Assembly

Applications: Arduino, Atom, CodeBlocks, Discord, Google Hangouts, MatLab, Microsoft Office Suite, Microsoft Visual Studio, Notepad++, PyCharm, Qt Creator, Skype, Slack, Spyder 3, Trello

Services/Methodologies: Agile, Azure, Back-End, BitBucket, Black Box Testing, Code Coverage, Continuous Integration, Doxygen, Dr. Memory, FakeItEasy, Front-End, Full Stack, Functional Testing, GitHub, GitLab, Google Docs, Integration Testing, Jenkins, KDiff3, log4net, Mecurial, Middleware, NUnit, ReSharper, Scrum, Test Driven Development, TortoiseHg, Unit Testing, White Box Testing, xUnit

EDUCATION

Oregon Institute of Technology (OregonTech)

06/2018

BS | Software Engineering Technology

Minor in Applied Mathematics Graduated Magna Cum Laude | 3.76 GPA

Relevant coursework:

Advanced Technical Writing Computer Architecture Computer Network Communications Cryptography

Database Systems and Design

Data Structures and Algorithms Design Patterns Discrete Mathematics GUI Programming Linear Algebra Object Oriented Programming Operating Systems Small Group / Team Communications Software Testing Web Design and Development

PROJECTS

AVIATION MAINTENANCE MANAGEMENT SYSTEM (AMMS) - SENIOR PROJECT 2018

Derived from the U.S. Army's current maintenance software using modern software development techniques. Has the capacity to manage records for all aviation units in the Army. Individual user accounts with multiple user roles allowing access to role-based maintenance tasks. Records flights, inspections, faults and maintenance actions.

Sole developer for this project.

C# ASP.NET Core 2.0 full stack web application

- Used GitHub source control management service
- Used object modeling to implement the Model View Controller (MVC) design pattern
- Built a Microsoft SQL Server database using LINQ and Entity framework for access
- Used modern software design principles to use a repository and control access to the database
- Built custom services and security protocols for transferring data between views and repositories
- Created Razor/HTML structured web pages
- Used CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, and Bootstrap for web page design
- Implemented NUnit Testing framework in combination with FakeltEasy Mocking to test features
- Included Log4Net Logging service for error reporting and path tracing during development
- Currently hosted online with Microsoft Azure

AARON DAY

MOVIE INVENTORY DATABASE (CAPA MOVIES) - JUNIOR PROJECT 2017

Online movie inventory system, which allows users to manage all of their movies regardless of the format. Locate movies across media platforms to know exactly what you have and where you have it. Review movie information from Online Movie DataBase (OMDB) and Rotten Tomatoes. Give the movies a personal rating and loan physical copies of movies to your friends. Multiple view and sort options.

4 person team project. My role/responsibilities: Project Owner, Database Manager, Tester C# ASP.NET Core 1.0 full-stack web application

- · Adopted the Agile development methodology with weekly scrum meetings and bi-weekly sprints for product development
- Utilized GitLab for source control and user story management
- Responsible for the initial project build using the Model View Controller (MVC) design pattern
- Built and maintained the Microsoft SQL Server database using LINQ and Entity framework for access
- Implemented the xUnit Testing framework
- Developed controller methods for various sorting options within the views

ORTHOGONAL FREQUENCY DIVISION MULTIPLEXING – LINEAR ALGEBRA II PROJECT 2018

Method of encoding digital data on multiple carrier frequencies. Simulates the function of a wireless transmitter and receiver as well as noise encountered during transmission.

- Developed in MatLab
- Converts data into a binary bit stream
- Modulates the bit stream into a symbol stream using Phase Shift Keying (PSK)
- Maps the symbols to an FFT carrier package
- Inserts pilot signals into the package
- Uses Inverse Fast Fourier Transform (IFFT) to convert signal into time domain for transmission
- Adds cyclic prefixing to help with interference
- Simulates transmission noise
- Receives transmission and reverses process to obtain data stream

ENIGMA - CRYPTOGRAPHY PROJECT 2017

Fully functional software version of the World War II Nazi Enigma machine. Allows the user to choose one of three reflector rotors, three of eight standard rotors, ring settings for each installed rotor, initial settings for rotors and up to 13 plug board cable settings. Includes keyboard, light board, and input/output display.

- Developed in C#
- Used Windows Forms for the Graphic User Interface

WORK EXPERIENCE

L3 Vertex Aerospace 10/2010 – 11/2012

H-60 Technical Inspector

- Trained mechanics and inspectors on the use of the ULLS-A(E) maintenance management software
- Developed multiple Microsoft Excel programs to manage personnel time on active work orders/expense accounts, aircraft rigging, cable tension checks, fuel integrity tests, aviation maintenance messages, inspection checklists, and phase packets

ARINC 08/2008 – 10/2010

AIT Analyst / UID SME

- Constructed 2-dimensional barcodes to track military aviation assets, tools, weapons, and aviation life support equipment
- Registered the barcodes with the national UID registry
- Trained military personnel on the use of specialized inventory management software, including adding/removing/querying database items.

MILITARY EXPERIENCE

United States Army 11/2001 – 10/2007 Tennessee Army National Guard 11/2007 – 10/2010